Ali Raza

Lahore, 54590 Punjab, Pakistan +92 305 7381431 Github: <u>alirazamumtaz</u> LinkedIn: <u>alirazamumtaz</u> Webiste: <u>alirazamumtaz.me</u> Email: elirazamumtaz@gmail.com

Research Interests

My research interests lie in the intersection of computer security and low-level systems. I am interested in the security vulnerabilities posed by systems, and how they can be exploited. For now, I am working on my FYP thesis that is about reproducing CVE-2019-2215 which is the Use After Free vulnerability in Android Kernel's Binder IPC subsystem.

Education

PUCIT - University of the Punjab

Bachelor of Science - Computer Science

- Expected graduation: July 2023
- GPA: 3.65/4.0

Punjab Group of Colleges, Okara Campus

Intermediate of Computer Science with Physics

• Graduated with 3rd position in BISE Sahiwal.

September, 2019 – Present

2017 - 2019

Lahore, Punjab, Pakistan

Okara, Punjab, Pakistan

Research Experience

Vulnerability Research and Exploit Development for Android Kernel

July, 2022 – Present

PUCIT - University of the Punjab

- Supervisor: Dr. Muhammad Arif Butt
- Formulated the idea and initiated the research project
- Worked on problems related to memory errors in binaries
- Worked on reversing binaries using IDA Freeware
- Worked on chroot jailbreak
- · Working on analysing Linux kernel

Professional Experience

Teaching Assistant (Operating Systems)

October, 2022 - Present

PUCIT - University of the Punjab

Lahore, Punjab, Pakistan

- Designed material and coursework for the newly introduced lab component of the subject
- Designed exam papers for the lab
- Assisted students in the lab + other TA responsibilities

Programming Tutor

April, 2022 - Present

Fiverr.com

Freelance on Fiverr

- Teaching low level programming concepts in C
- Teaching object oriented programming in C++

Programming Languages: C, Python, Java, C#, x86-64 Assembly

Security: Binary Exploitation, Reverse Engineering

Tools: IDA, GDB, GNU/Make

OS: MacOS, Linux

Projects

Unix Shell C, Makefile

https://github.com/alirazamumtaz/unix-shell

An effort to write the *nix based shell to gain understanding of how shell works and how OS
creates and handles processes and allows processes to communicate with each other through it's
IPC interface

Exploits Scripts Python, x86 Assembly

https://github.com/alirazamumtaz/exploit-development

• Basic scripts that I have written to solve some exploitation challenges

Hack Assembler C++

https://github.com/alirazamumtaz/hack-assembler

• A 16-bit machine language assembler for the 16-bit Hack Assembly Language. This was done as part of building a complete 16-bit computer during the Computer Organization Assembly Language Course

Courses & MOOCs

Computer Systems Security: pwn.college

- Shellcode Injection
- Sandboxing
- Reverse Engineering
- Memory Errors
- Race Conditions
- Kernel Security
- Program Exploitation

Extracurriculars & Volunteering

Club Leader

PUCIT - University of the Punjab

2021 – 2022 & 2022 – Present

Google Developer Student Clubs

- Faculty Contact: Assist. Prof. Abdul Mateen
- Organized tech workshops and seminars
- E.g. CodeFest, Hacktoberfest, etc

Event Organiser

Event Management Society

- Organized inter-college events
- E.g. Job Fair, Trips, etc

PUCIT - University of the Punjab 2020 - 2021 & 2022 - Present

Awards & Honors

Board Topper 2019

Intermediate - BISE Sahiwal
• https://pgc.edu/our-achievers/

Sahiwal, Pakistan

 Awarded with a brass medal and a cash prize by the Board of Intermediate and Secondary Education, Sahiwal